George W. Childs Letters
George W. Childs Letters
1862-1892
Childs, George W. (George William), 1829-1894.
1 folder (SC)
The papers of the American publisher include correspondence concerning the work of Benson J. Lossing, and some letters about the Public Ledger Almanac.
149187
Biographical History
George William Childs (1829-1894) was an American editor and publisher. His letters mainly include correspondence with Benson John Lossing (1813-1891), an American author remembered for his illustrated works.
Born in Maryland on May 12, 1829, Childs is known as both a publisher and philanthropist. Childs was an American editor and publisher, who founded the Philadelphia Public Ledger. He was married to Emma Bouvier Peterson. Childs died of a stroke on February 3, 1894.
The George W. Childs Letters primarily concern the work of historian Benson John Lossing. Lossing was born February 12, 1813 in Beekman, New York to John and Miriam Dorland Lossing. He is best known for his illustrated works of American history, such as his Pictorial Field Books of the American Revolution, the War of 1812, and the Civil War. He died on June 3, 1891 of a heart attack.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The George W. Childs Letters primarily concern the work of historian Benson Lossing, together with a few items about the Public Ledger Almanac. The correspondents who write of Lossing's project are: George Mifflin Dallas, Isaac Ferris, John Wien Forney, Frederick Holbrook, Theophilus Parsons, Barnas Sears, and Francis Wayland.
Included in the collection are a few personal letters, including those from Sarah Knowles Bolton and Laura Colwell. Among the outgoing personal letters is an item to W. A. Seaver in which Childs mentions a recent dinner party which was attended by Ralph Waldo Emerson at this home, and a congratulatory message to Edwards Pierrepont upon his appointment as Attorney-General of the United States.
Arrangement of the Collection
The correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Bolton, Sarah Knowles, 1841-1916.; Childs, George W. (George William), 1829-1894.; Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864.; Ferris, Isaac, 1798-1873.; Forney, John W. (John Wien), 1817-1881.; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896.; Lossing, Benson John, 1813-1891.; Parsons, Theophilus, 1797-1882.; Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892.; Scharf, J. Thomas (John Thomas), 1843-1898.; Sears, Barnas, 1802-1880.; Wayland, Francis, 1796-1865.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Correspondence.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Bolton, Sarah Knowles, 11 Jan 1892; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Colwell, Laura, undated; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Dallas, George Mifflin, 18 Mar 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Ferris, Isaac, Apr 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Forney, John Wien, 04 Apr 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 18 Sep 1862; 1 outgoing letter (Sc 29)
  - Holbrook, Frederick, 21 Mar 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Parsons, Theophilus, 04 Apr 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Pierrepont, Edwards, 30 Apr 1875; 1 outgoing letter (Sc 29)
  - Scharf, John Thomas, 16 Jan 1880; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Sears, Barnas, 05 May 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Seaver, W. A., 27 Mar 1875; 1 outgoing letter (Sc 29)
  - Stevens, Simon, 02 Jan 1864; 1 outgoing letter (Sc 29)
  - Usher, John Palmer, 09 Dec 1863; 1 outgoing letter (Sc 29)
  - Wayland, Francis, 01 May 1862; 1 incoming letter (Sc 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1864-1891; 4 outgoing, 3 incoming (Sc 29)